<?xml version="1.0"?>
<response><objects><object><category>Animals</category><causeid>1</causeid><description>Wildlife Conservation charities include fish, wildlife and bird refuges and sanctuaries, as well as groups researching wildlife protection and conservation around the globe.</description><cause>Wildlife Conservation</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/1/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/1/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Animals</category><causeid>2</causeid><description>Animal Rights, Welfare, and Services charities include humane societies and veterinary services; no-kill shelters, organizations protecting animals from cruelty, exploitation and other abuses; and groups providing animal training and specialty services, such as groups training guide dogs.</description><cause>Animal Rights, Welfare, and Services</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/1/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/2/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Arts, Culture, Humanities</category><causeid>3</causeid><description>Museums include traditional arts, science, technology, and natural history museums, as well as academies and institutes that provide training to practitioners in addition to maintaining collections.</description><cause>Museums</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/2/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/3/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Arts, Culture, Humanities</category><causeid>4</causeid><description>Performing Arts groups include symphonies, orchestras, and other musical groups; ballets and operas; theater groups; arts festivals; and performance halls and cultural centers.</description><cause>Performing Arts</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/2/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/4/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Arts, Culture, Humanities</category><causeid>5</causeid><description>Charities in Public Broadcasting and Media operate and support public television and radio stations and networks, as well as providing other independent media and communications services to the public.</description><cause>Public Broadcasting and Media</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/2/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/5/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Arts, Culture, Humanities</category><causeid>6</causeid><description>Charities in Libraries, Historical Societies and Landmark Preservation operate and support public and specialized libraries, historical societies, historical preservation programs, and historical estates.</description><cause>Libraries, Historical Societies and Landmark Preservation</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/2/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/6/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Education</category><causeid>7</causeid><description>Other Education Programs and Services include scholarship and financial aid services, organizations promoting school reform, environmental and other experiential learning programs, and programs supporting teachers, parents, students and schools.</description><cause>Other Education Programs and Services</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/3/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/7/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Education</category><causeid>8</causeid><description>Private Elementary and Secondary Schools are private institutions of learning that provide elementary and secondary education.</description><cause>Private Elementary and Secondary Schools</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/3/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/8/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Education</category><causeid>9</causeid><description>Universities, Graduate Schools, and Technological Institutes are institutions that support research and provide graduate and professional education, in addition to undergraduate coursework that they also make available.</description><cause>Universities, Graduate Schools, and Technological Institutes</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/3/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/9/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Environment</category><causeid>10</causeid><description>Botanical Gardens, Parks, and Nature Centers promote preservation and appreciation of the environment, as well as leading anti-litter, tree planting and other environmental beautification campaigns.</description><cause>Botanical Gardens, Parks, and Nature Centers</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/4/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/10/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Environment</category><causeid>11</causeid><description>Environmental Protection and Conservation charities develop ways to combat pollution; promote conservation and sustainable management of land, water, plant and energy resources; purchase and protect land; and develop more efficient uses of both energy and waste materials.</description><cause>Environmental Protection and Conservation</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/4/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/11/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Health</category><causeid>12</causeid><description>Treatment and Prevention Services charities are devoted to providing direct medical services and educating the public on ways to prevent diseases and reduce health risks.</description><cause>Treatment and Prevention Services</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/5/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/12/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Health</category><causeid>13</causeid><description>Charities in Diseases, Disorders, and Disciplines are multipurpose organizations that seek cures for particular diseases and disorders or promote particular medical disciplines by providing direct services, advocating for public understanding and support, and supporting targeted medical research.</description><cause>Diseases, Disorders, and Disciplines</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/5/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/13/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Health</category><causeid>14</causeid><description>Medical Research organizations focus the bulk of their efforts on researching causes and cures of disease and developing new treatments.</description><cause>Medical Research</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/5/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/14/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Human Services</category><causeid>15</causeid><description>Multipurpose Human Service Organizations promote volunteerism and provide a broad range of direct services in the communities they serve, across the nation and around the globe. These organizations include YMCAs, YWCAs, the Red Cross, Volunteers of America, and others.</description><cause>Multipurpose Human Service Organizations</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/6/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/15/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Human Services</category><causeid>16</causeid><description>Organizations providing Youth Development, Shelter, and Crisis Services work to shelter, nurture and develop youth. They include group homes, shelters and orphanages; camps and youth ranches serving the needs of at-risk children; and recreation and youth service organizations providing programs in scouting and athletics.</description><cause>Youth Development, Shelter, and Crisis Services</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/6/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/16/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Human Services</category><causeid>17</causeid><description>Children's and Family Services charities provide child care, adoption, foster care, family counseling, parenting education, and other adovacy and child welfare services that strengthen families and promote the well-being of our children.</description><cause>Children's and Family Services</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/6/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/17/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Human Services</category><causeid>18</causeid><description>Charities classified as Food Banks, Food Pantries, and Food Distribution provide hunger relief in communities throughout our country.</description><cause>Food Banks, Food Pantries, and Food Distribution</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/6/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/18/</resource_uri></object><object><category>International</category><causeid>19</causeid><description>Charities working for International Peace, Security, and Affairs include cultural and student exchange programs; organizations promoting peace and security; human rights groups; groups promoting improved relations between particular countries; organizations providing foreign policy research and advocacy; and United Nations-related organizations.</description><cause>International Peace, Security, and Affairs</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/7/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/19/</resource_uri></object><object><category>International</category><causeid>20</causeid><description>Development and Relief Service charities provide medical care and other human services as well as economic, educational, and agricultural development services to people around the world.</description><cause>Development and Relief Services</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/7/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/20/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Public Benefit</category><causeid>21</causeid><description>Advocacy and Civil Rights includes government watchdogs; groups protecting civil and legal rights; advocacy organizations educating voters and influencing public policy; charities promoting the rights and welfare of our armed services veterans; and groups promoting understanding and tolerance among racial, ethnic and cultural groups.</description><cause>Advocacy and Civil Rights</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/8/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/21/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Public Benefit</category><causeid>22</causeid><description>Community Foundations promote giving by managing long-term donor-advised charitable funds for individual givers, much like a mutual fund for giving, and by distributing those funds to community-based charities over time on behalf of givers.</description><cause>Community Foundations</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/8/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/22/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Public Benefit</category><causeid>23</causeid><description>Fundraising Organizations include United Ways, Jewish Federations, art councils, and other fundraising campaigns. They raise money through annual fundraising campaigns and distribute those funds to community-based charities and to charities addressing various public and cultural issues.</description><cause>Fundraising Organizations</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/8/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/23/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Public Benefit</category><causeid>24</causeid><description>Research and Public Policy Institutions include think tanks and social science research facilities that study various public policy and social issues, as well as those institutes providing research and services in non-medical sciences, engineering, and technology.</description><cause>Research and Public Policy Institutions</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/8/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/24/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Religion</category><causeid>25</causeid><description>Religious Media and Broadcasting includes organizations of all faiths that produce and distribute religious programming, literature, and other communications.</description><cause>Religious Media and Broadcasting</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/9/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/25/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Religion</category><causeid>26</causeid><description>Religious Activities includes those charities supporting and promoting various faiths.</description><cause>Religious Activities</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/9/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/26/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Public Benefit</category><causeid>27</causeid><description>Charities in Community and Housing Development lead and finance development projects that increase access to affordable housing, revitalize our communities, and enhance our public and private institutions.</description><cause>Community and Housing Development</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/8/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/27/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Human Services</category><causeid>28</causeid><description>Charities in the Homeless Services Cause provide assistance to homeless individuals and families through direct social services as well as advocacy.</description><cause>Homeless Services</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/6/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/28/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Human Services</category><causeid>29</causeid><description>Social Services charities provide programs addressing the needs of the disadvantaged, the underemployed, the elderly and disabled, and other specific populations. They also include community centers and settlement houses that provide integrated services for local communities.</description><cause>Social Services</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/6/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/29/</resource_uri></object><object><category>International</category><causeid>30</causeid><description>Charities in Humanitarian Relief Supplies specialize in collecting donated medical, food, agriculture, and other supplies and distributing them overseas to those in need.</description><cause>Humanitarian Relief Supplies</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/7/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/30/</resource_uri></object><object><category>International</category><causeid>31</causeid><description>Foreign Charity Support Organizations raise funds for organizations in or provide aid to foreign countries.</description><cause>Foreign Charity Support Organizations</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/7/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/31/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Animals</category><causeid>32</causeid><description>Charities classified as Zoos and Aquariums are charities which operate zoos, aquariums and zoological societies in communities throughout the country.</description><cause>Zoos and Aquariums</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/1/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/32/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Education</category><causeid>33</causeid><description>Private Liberal Arts Colleges are private institutions of higher learning that provide liberal arts education.</description><cause>Private Liberal Arts Colleges</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/3/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/33/</resource_uri></object><object><category>Health</category><causeid>34</causeid><description>Patient and Family Support organizations offer wish granting programs, camping programs, housing or travel assistance and other services for family members and patients that are diagnosed with a serious illness.</description><cause>Patient and Family Support</cause><categoryid>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/categories/5/</categoryid><resource_uri>http://api.charitynavigator.org/api/v1/causes/34/</resource_uri></object></objects></response>
